(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 1,
"subtitles": 2
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
録音、録画、SNSへの動画や音声アップロードは固くお断りいたします
Audio / video recordings and illegal uploads are strictly prohibited.
スクリーンショットをSNSにアップロードは拡散OK!
Sharing screenshots on social media is OK!
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
2025.2.1 21:30~ ライブグッズ 2次販売開始
Feb 1, 2025 21:30~ Live Goods 2nd Sale Starting
Hoshimachi Suisei 日本武道館 Live "SuperNova"
Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live "SuperNova"
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
録音、録画、ミラー配信や無断アップロードは固く禁止いたします
Audio/video recordings, mirror streams and illegal uploads are strictly prohibited.
スクリーンショットをSNSにアップロードはOK！SNSでの拡散大歓迎！
Feel free to share screenshots and reactions on social media.
Attention
ご来場のお客様へ
To our guests
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください。
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
Hoshimachi Suisei 日本武道館 Live "SuperNova"
Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live "SuperNova"
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Sponsors
協賛
JOYSOUND
FuRyU
歌いたい曲が入っていなかった
The song I wanted to sing wasn't there.
だったらJOYSOUND X1で歌おうぜ
In that case, let's sing with JOYSOUND X1!
JOYSOUND X1 Only One
JOYSOUND X1 曲数No.1
JOYSOUND X1, number one in song count
AIが採点絶賛 カラオケ最高
AI scoring is highly acclaimed, karaoke is the best!
JOYSOUND Revolution We go On
JOYSOUND X1
彗星のごとく現れたスターの原石！
A stellar raw gem that appeared like a comet!
バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
I'm virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
この度、フリューさんから
This time, from FuRyu,
わたしの新作プライズアイテムが登場します！
my new prize items are coming out!
新作アイテムは全部で4種類！
There are four types of new items in total!
みんな絶対ゲットしてね！
Everyone, make sure to get them!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To our guests
演出の都合上、照明の点滅にご注意ください
Please be aware of flashing lights during the performance.
声出し応援OKです
Cheering loudly is OK.
2025.2.1 21:30- ライブグッズ2次販売開始
2025.2.1 21:30 - Live Goods 2nd Round Sales Start
Hoshimachi Suisei 日本武道館 Live SUPERNOVA
Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live SUPERNOVA
武道館ライブおめでとうございます！
すいちゃんに出会えて本当によかったです！
Congratulations on your Budokan live!
I'm so glad I met you, Sui-chan!
夢が叶う瞬間を一緒に過ごせて幸せです。
いつまでも応援しています！
I'm happy to witness your dream come true.
I'll always be rooting for you!
Congratulations on your Budokan Live!
祝 武道館 ライブ
Celebrating the Budokan Live
Start our dream stage!
SUPER NOVA
Budokan! I am witnessing history...
I will support you until the end!
Congratulations on achieving
Dream of Performing at Budokan
ずっとずっとついていきます！
夢の舞台へ！！
I will follow you forever!
To the stage of dreams!!
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
Attention ご来場の皆様へ
Attention To all attendees
演出の都合上、照明の明滅にご注意ください
声出し応援OKです
Please be aware of flashing lights.
Cheering loudly is OK.
祝 武道館ライブ！
すいちゃん、大好きです！！
Celebrating the Budokan live!
Sui-chan, I love you!!
Hoshimachi Suisei 日本武道館 Live SUPERNOVA
Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live SUPERNOVA
「星街すいせい 日本武道館 Live “SuperNova”」にご来場いただきまして、
Thank you very much for coming to "Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live 'SuperNova',"
誠にありがとうございます。
we truly appreciate your presence.
イエーイ！
Yeah!
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
To ensure everyone enjoys the live until the end, I have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影・録音・録画機材の使用は、固くお断りいたします。
The use of photography, audio recording, or video recording equipment during the performance is strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮くださいますよう、お願い申し上げます。
Smoking is prohibited inside the venue. We kindly ask that you refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
In the unlikely event that you feel unwell, please don't push yourself and inform a nearby staff member.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、
Moshing and diving within the venue,
ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他のみんなの迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
throwing objects onto the stage, or any other actions that bother others or interfere with the performance are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってください。
Please follow the rules and have a great time.
また、
Also,
本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
there are cameras in the venue for video distribution and photography, and the audience seats may be captured.
これらの映像や写真は、プロモーションなどに使用される可能性がございますので、予めご了承ください。
Please be aware that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
はーい！
Okay!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは「#駆け抜ける星街」です。
Also, the hashtag for the live is "#駆け抜ける星街" (#KakenukeruHoshimachi).
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください。
Please use the hashtag and build up the excitement!
よろしい！
Good!
それでは、開演まであと、もう少しです！
Well then, there's only a little while longer until the show starts!
みんなで一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Let's all get excited together!
またね！
See you later!
鉄壁
Ironclad
Hoshimachi Suisei
Hoshimachi Suisei 日本武道館 Live
SUPERNOVA
Hoshimachi Suisei Nippon Budokan Live
Bibideba Bibideba...
つまんないって吠ざんね　奇跡願ってるだけの人生
Don't bark that it's boring, a life just wishing for miracles.
Watch me do-do-do-do to the hi-hi-hit trick な粋の magic
Watch me do-do-do-do to the hi-hi-hit trick, a stylish magic.
I wanna be free だってまだ feel us...
I wanna be free, because I still feel us...
兵隊靴に　ちょっと宇宙まで
In soldier boots, off to space for a bit.
秒針は音立てないで　夜を急かす魔物のよう
The second hand makes no sound, like a monster rushing the night.
人生は一瞬にして　解ける魔法
Life is a magic that dissolves in an instant.
それならば駆け抜けてみたいの my baby
If that's the case, I want to run through it, my baby.
おしゃまなパソで飛び出す世界　私は大変身 make up
Dashing out into the world with cheeky steps, I'll have a big transformation, make up.
わがまま money money きらめきに chu chu
Selfish money money, chu chu to the sparkle.
空の間で dancing さよなら goodbye bitter
Dancing in the space of the sky, farewell, goodbye bitter.
いつかは喝采クラップ audience　みなみなご唱和あれ
Someday, applause and claps from the audience, everyone sing along.
Bibideba Bibideba...
こんがらがってもしょうがない
It's no use getting all tangled up.
こんがらがってもチョー可愛いから
Even if you're all mixed up, you're super cute
正気じゃいられない
I can't stay sane
BIBBIDI BOOWA BIBBIDI BOOWA
こんな明日どないならば
If tomorrow's like this, then...
急にどたまカチでしょう
Suddenly, my head's gonna snap
0と1で構成された　意味のない Lights
Meaningless lights composed of zeros and ones
誰にも見せないままで
Keeping them hidden from everyone
天蓋　孤独　濁らせて歌い出せ
Canopy, solitude, let them cloud over and start singing
In case I don't see you, 夢に出てきてあげる
In case I don't see you, I'll appear in your dreams
歪んでいる復讐心も今笑ってあげる
I'll laugh away even that warped vengeful heart now
妄想じゃないの　だってあなたとほら
It's not a delusion, because look, with you...
Tu-lu-lu-lu-lu
衝撃の最前線　毒を食らわばイイイ
At the front lines of impact, if you're going to eat poison, eat it all
処すもの　されるもの　全部壊して
Those who judge and those who are judged, break it all down
暴れまくってぶち込め
Go wild and throw it all in
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
A star in the making that appeared like a comet! I'm virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃーーーん！？
Sui-chaーーn!?
革命の準備　終わらせるスキップ
Preparations for revolution, a skip to end it all
乗り越える肝は　怖くないスケープ
The key to getting over it is an escape without fear
Shubi-dubi-dubi-dubi-dubi-du... Voice to the Grave!
君も君も　濁ってる復讐心も抱きしめてあげる
You, and you too, I'll embrace even your clouded vengeful hearts
妄想じゃないの　だってあなたとほら
It's not a delusion, because look, with you...
Tu-lu-lu-lu-lu
想像の先だって　楽しそうに歌う
Even beyond imagination, I sing happily
嘘じゃない　濁ってる復讐心も
It's no lie, even those clouded vengeful hearts
何万回と再生した　希望の救済
Salvation of hope, replayed tens of thousands of times
居るべき場所　意義　意味　有象無象みんな探してる
A place to belong, significance, meaning, everyone is searching amidst the masses
手のひらに答えがなけりゃ
If the answer isn't in the palm of your hand...
Boom Out! 関係ない　奏でようさあ
Boom Out! It doesn't matter, come on, let's play
君も君も　濁ってる復讐心も今笑ってあげる
You, and you too, I'll laugh away even those clouded vengeful hearts now
妄想じゃないの　だってあなたとほら
It's not a delusion, because look, with you...
Tu-lu-lu-lu-lu
正教じゃない　理論だって間違いだ
It's not orthodox, even the theories are wrong
嘘じゃない　あれもこれも愛ゆえでしょう
It's no lie, all of this must be because of love
濁ってる復讐心も抱きしめてあげる
I'll embrace even your clouded vengeful hearts
消えきった太陽に見放されて
Abandoned by the freezing sun
ずっと縛り付けられている星の上
Eternally tied down to the top of this star
逆らってメッセージが流れ出して
A defiant message begins to flow
街の上で砕けていく
Shattering over the streets
きっと誰もただ一人で
Surely everyone is all alone
拳を握りながら 藻掻きながら泣いてるんだ
Crying as they clench their fists and struggle
「愛してる」「大嫌い」「大好き」
"I love you," "I hate you," "I love you"
だって重いくらいの想いが溢れる
Because feelings as heavy as my thoughts overflow
今日も矛盾して咲いてくこの感情が
These emotions that bloom in contradiction again today
音の中で初めて光り合うんだね
Begin to shine for the first time within the sound
歌の中で初めて響き出すんだね
Begin to resonate for the first time within the song
冷めきった対応と並んだ表情に
To the cold treatment and expressionless faces
臆病になってた街の上
I became cowardly over the streets
叶わない暴力と史上稀な重力に
By invincible violence and extremely rare gravity
名前も何も決め付けられている
My name and everything else is already decided
なんてどこかで吐いた言い訳が
Such excuses spat out somewhere
声を奪ったまま荷物みたいになってたんだ 今更
Took away my voice and became like baggage, after all this time
変われない 分かってよ 信じて 嘘つき
Can't change, understand me, believe me, liar
嫌になるくらいの想いが渦巻く
Feelings that make me sick are swirling
今日も振り回されてく無力な足が
Today again, my powerless legs are being dragged along
飛び上がる準備をしてる
Preparing to take flight
何もかも反発して 崩壊して滲んでいく
Everything repels, collapses, and blurs
みんなの歌声聴かせてください！
Everyone, let me hear your voices!
Clap clap!
否定したい 信じたい 嘘だよ そうだよ
I want to deny, I want to believe, it's a lie, that's right
嫌いじゃない 好きじゃない 全部が 一つが
I don't hate, I don't love, all of it, just one thing
変わりたい 分かりたい どうしよう どうしよう
I want to change, I want to understand, what should I do, what should I do
聴かせない 聴かせて
I won't let you hear, let me hear
伝えたい「愛してる」「大嫌い」「大好き」
I want to tell you, "I love you," "I hate you," "I love you"
だって重いくらいの想いの先まで
Because beyond the feelings as heavy as my thoughts
今日もまた歌い叫んでるこの感情が
These emotions that I'm singing and screaming out again today
音の中で初めて光り合うまで
Until they begin to shine within the sound
あなたのその胸で響き出すまで
Until they begin to resonate in your heart
「愛してる」
“I love you”
「大嫌い」
“I hate you”
「嘘だよ」
“It's a lie”
「大好き」
“I love you”
ということで、皆さん、こんにちは！
And with that, hello everyone!
では、いつもの挨拶いかせていただきます。
Now, let's go with the usual greeting.
お！彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
O! A diamond in the rough, polished to shine like a comet! I'm virtual idol Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー！
Sui-chan is—!
いいですね、武道館！
Looking good, Budokan!
水飲みます、失礼します。
I'm going to drink some water, excuse me.
はあ、もうね、しょっぱなから
Wow, already, right from the start,
クライマックスみたいな感じになってるんですけども...
it feels like the climax of the show...
星街すいせい 日本武道館ライブ
Hoshimachi Suisei's Nippon Budokan live
「SuperNova」、いよいよ始まりました！
'SuperNova' has finally begun!
うわぁ、すごい。ついにこの日がやってきたのか。
Wow, incredible. This day has finally arrived.
ね、感慨深いね、みんな。
Right? It's deeply moving, everyone.
はあ、えー、もうみんな知ってると思うんですけど...
Sigh... Um, I think everyone already knows, but...
えー、デビュー当初からね、ずっと、あの、
Ever since my debut, I've always
武道館でライブをするぞというのを目標にしてやってきたんですけど...
had the goal of performing a live concert at Budokan...
ついにね、立てたということで、あの、本日は
And now I'm finally standing here, so today
サードアルバムの曲をいっぱいやる予定ですので。
I plan to perform many songs from my third album.
みんな聴いてきたかな？サードアルバムちゃんと。
Did everyone listen to it? The third album, properly.
そりゃそうだよね。あ、みんなサードアルバムの中で
Of course you did. Oh, which one from the third album
どれが楽しみ？
are you looking forward to?
うんうん、わかんない。ははは。
Yeah, yeah, I can't tell. Hahaha.
はい、えー、今回もツアーと同じくバンドさんを引き連れております！
Yes, um, this time too, just like the tour, I've brought the band along!
さらに、えー、皆さん気づかれたでしょうか。
Furthermore, um, did you all notice?
そう、今回はブラス隊もいるんです！
Yes, this time we have a brass section too!
イェーイ。はい、今日しか聴けないようなね、
Yeah. Yes, I've created many live arrangements
ライブアレンジをバンドさんと一緒にいっぱい作ってきましたので。
with the band that you can only hear today.
おー、あ、ハードル上げちゃった。ははは。
Oh, ah, I've raised the bar. Hahaha.
いや本当にね、いい感じにアレンジされてるので、全部楽しみにしててください。
But really, they've been arranged so well, so please look forward to all of them.
えー、では、これが推しカメラです。
Um, well, this is the 'fav cam'.
イェーイ。うわーい。いやみんなさ、
Yay. Whoo-hoo. Hey, everyone,
気づいた？あの、ツアーしたツアーと一緒で、
did you notice? It's like the tour outfit,
あの、上だけちょっとアタッチメント変わって、みたいな衣装なんですよ、今回は。
but for this time, just the top part has a different attachment.
「わかりやす、さすがに」って？え、そうだよね。そうなんですよ。
"It's obvious"? Oh, right. That's true.
あの、ツアーで、ツアーでもう実は着れる、着れたんですけど、
Actually, I could have worn this during the tour,
この服、もう出来上がってたから。
because the outfit was already finished.
でもちょっと出し惜しみしとこうかな武道館にと思って出し惜しみしときました。
But I thought I'd save it for Budokan, so I held back.
たくさんスクショしてください。わーい。
Please take lots of screenshots. Yay.
ピース。なんかこれピースみたいな格好じゃないよな。
Peace. Wait, this doesn't really look like a peace pose.
はい、えー、ライブの感想は #駆け巡る星街 でたくさんツイートしてください。
Yes, um, please tweet your concert impressions with #駆け巡る星街.
スクショOK。
Screenshots are OK.
YouTube, TikTokでご覧の方は、はっ、ここまでです！
For those watching on YouTube and TikTok, ha, this is the end!
はい、YouTube, TikTokの皆さんの分まで「えー」いただきました。
Yes, I got enough "ehhh"s for the YouTube and TikTok viewers as well.
えー、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは
Um, those of you who want to keep getting hyped together,
概要欄から配信サイトへ飛んでくださいね。こっちか、こっちか、こっちか。
please go to the streaming site from the description. Is it here, or here, or here?
ということでね、あの、もうさっきも言ったんですけど、
So, um, like I said earlier,
冒頭からクライマックスみたいなセットリストをしているんですが...
I've put together a setlist that's like a climax right from the start...
私がこのセトリ考えて、あの、バンドリハやった時に
When I thought of this setlist and did the band rehearsals,
「これ、ずっとクライマックスだな」って。
I thought, "This is just one long climax."
いや本当にずっとクライマックスなんですよ。
No, really, it's a climax the whole time.
だからもうね、皆さんも感情がこんな、こんな、こんな状態に、
So, your emotions are going to be like this, like this, like this,
もうこうなっちゃうから、あの、水分補給しつつ楽しんでいただければと思います。
just all over the place, so please stay hydrated and enjoy.
ふう、あ、今のうちに皆さんあの、ペンライト見たい。
Whew... Oh, while we're at it, I want to see everyone's penlights.
うわ、あとなんか、うちわとか見たい、うちわ。
Wow, and also, I want to see some fans, the hand fans.
あ、ありがとう、ありがとう、ありがとう。おー見る見る見る見る。
Ah, thank you, thank you, thank you. Oh, I see them, I see them.
嬉しい、今日のためにみんな作ってくれたんだもんね。
I'm so happy, you all made them for today, didn't you?
いつもみんなさ、ちゃんとさ見れてないからさ、ちゃんと見とこうと思って。今のうちに。
I usually can't see everyone properly, so I wanted to take a good look. While I can.
この後何が起こるかわかんないからね。よし。
Because I don't know what's going to happen next. Alright.
ちょっと、ちょっとなんか変なこと言ってるな。別に普通にライブが行われますんで。
Wait, I'm saying something a bit weird. The live concert will proceed normally.
では、皆さんもう次の曲聴きたいですか？
Now, does everyone want to hear the next song already?
ちょっと乾燥してるんで、もう一回水飲みます。
My throat's a bit dry, so I'll drink some water again.
それでは 次の曲は
So, for the next song...
私の思いを込めて
...I've poured my heart and soul into it.
初の作曲に挑戦した
It's the first song I've ever composed,
あの曲です。
and this is that song.
聴いてください。
Please listen.
綺麗事。
Lip Service.
LIP SERVICE
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free portion of the stream has ended. Thank you for watching!
Thank you for coming! Please share your thoughts on social media!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The free portion has ended. Thank you for watching!